<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!--This XML file contains all the copy for the site. Edit as needed.-->
<root>
    <meta>
        <title>Jason Chaney | Professional Web Application Development</title>
    </meta>
    <intro>I am a seasoned web developer that adheres to the highest level of semantic standards and architectures. I
        have over 13 years of cutting-edge experience working for agencies, direct clients, companies and individuals.
        My passion is rooted in finding efficiency in digital communication though visual arts. I have experience
        leading distributed development teams, executing social campaigns, utilizing/building web services, prototyping
        new concepts, developing mobile initiatives and optimizing workflows.
    </intro>
    <about>
        <title>Who is this Guy?</title>
        <subtitle>I'm a full-stack front-end developer.</subtitle>
        <culture>
            <title>
                My Culture
            </title>
            <body>
                <![CDATA[
                <p>
                The techniques, tools and architecture patterns used to create the modern web literally change
                everyday. As a professional developer, I consider it my responsibility to constantly keep up. I
                listen to podcasts, follow industry leaders on Twitter and collaborate with other professionals
                daily to ensure I'm using the absolute latest resources available when project crunch time hits.</p>
                ]]>
            </body>
        </culture>
        <body>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>I specialize in building responsive, mobile-first interactive solutions. I focus on
                usability and architecture while
                ensuring code conforms to the highest level of web and
                <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming">OOP</a>
                semantic standards. I enjoy keeping up with bleeding-edge tools, techniques and new technologies.
                Check out
                my process to hear how.
            </p>
            ]]>
        </body>
        <freetime>
            <title>
                In My Free Time
            </title>
            <dad>
                <title>Dad</title>
                <image>img/Jason-Chaney.jpg</image>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    I have two beautiful twin
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/20130522-184111.jpg" target="_blank">daughters</a>
                    that keep my wife and I on our toes. We keep a family
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com" target="_blank">blog</a>
                    for
                    friends and family to keep up with the Chaney's
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/archives/1763" target="_blank">antics</a>.
                    ]]>
                </body>
            </dad>
            <technology>
                <title>Technology</title>
                <image>img/segway.jpg</image>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    I enjoy making
                    <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QWfmhuk8cAM" target="_blank">tutorials</a>
                    for other developers, <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/archives/617" target="_blank">hacking</a>
                    a baby swing,
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/archives/953" target="_blank">pulling my kids</a>

                    behind my
                    Segway
                    or learning new technologies like <a href="http://codeception.com/" target="_blank">Codeception</a>.
                    ]]>
                </body>

            </technology>
            <code>
                <title>Code</title>
                <image>img/jason_workstation.jpg</image>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                        I love all things code.
                            Finding new ways to optimize a method, app, animation or even my monitor setup makes me
                            jump up like <a href="img/boris.jpg" target="_blank">Boris</a>
                         in Goldeneye.  In fact, this entire site is powered by one <a href="/data" target="_blank">data file</a>.
                    ]]>
                </body>
            </code>
        </freetime>
    </about>
    <contact>
        <title>Get in Touch</title>
        <subtitle>If you think I can help out on a project, drop me a line.</subtitle>
        <name>Jason Chaney</name>
        <address>5120 Hill Villa Ave S</address>
        <company>Creative Acceleration, Inc.</company>
        <city>Salem</city>
        <state>OR</state>
        <zip>97306</zip>
        <country>US</country>
        <phone>310-433-6322</phone>
        <email>
            <ca>jason@creativeacceleration.com</ca>
            <personal>jason@jasonchaney.com</personal>
        </email>
    </contact>
    <process>
        <title>
            My Process
        </title>
        <subtitle>What separates me from other developers?</subtitle>
        <body>
            <![CDATA[
            If you ask a developer what they use to make a website, one might say<a
                href="http://www.adobe.com/products/dreamweaver.html" target="_blank">Dreamweaver</a>,
            another might say
            <a href="http://wordpress.org/" target="_blank">Wordpress</a>
            or
            <a href="http://www.squarespace.com/" target="_blank">Squarespace</a>
            and another might
            say
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_(text_editor)">Vim</a>
            or<a href="http://nodejs.org/" target="_blank">Node</a>.

            Just this one answer can tell you tons about the nature of those developers. While it doesn't
            necessarily provide a way to know which one might be more skilled at software architecture, it does
            tell
            you which one probably has more knowledge that reaches beyond the average script-kiddies.
              ]]>
        </body>
        <asside>
            I have talked to many developers who say they know JavaScript, when in fact what they really know is
            how
            to modify
            <a href="http://jquery.com/" target="_blank">jQuery</a>
            code. What I do here is outline the general approach and tools I use for interactive project
            construction. This should give you a good idea as to the type of developer I am.
        </asside>
        <points>
            <point>
                <headline>The Editor...or rather IDE</headline>
                <body>
                    A good text editor will do things like syntax
                    highlighting. A great editor will do things like code completion. But an awesome editor is not
                    an
                    editor at all, It's an
                    <a
                            href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment">IDE
                    </a>
                    or Integrated
                    Development Environment. Some common IDE's are<a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</a>,
                    Apple's<a href="http://developer.apple.com/tools/xcode/">xCode</a>,
                    <a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/flash-builder.html">Flash Builder</a>
                    (Built on Eclipse),
                    <a href="http://www.appcelerator.com/">Appcelerator</a>
                    and<a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/webstorm/">Webstorm</a>. Personally, I use
                    <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/">IntelliJ</a>. The big reason to use an IDE is because
                    text editors like
                    <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank">Sublime Text</a>
                    simply
                    understand the piece of code you're writing, but IDE's understand how it all connects. This is
                    an invaluable distinction and can save untold amounts
                    of
                    time both on the development and debugging sides.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Build Process</headline>
                <body>
                    Websites and apps have grown to a complexity level that they now require more robust techniques
                    for deployment, code optimization and overall organization. The industry standard tool for doing
                    this is
                    <a href="http://gruntjs.com/" target="_blank">Grunt</a>
                    and I love to find
                    ever-efficient ways to build projects for both development and production with it. I use grunt
                    for many tasks including deployment, image optimization, CSS/JS complication, Linting and
                    minifying.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Version Control</headline>
                <body>
                    Any developer that doesn't use version control doesn't understand the benefits, and
                    therefore probably has not worked in a team environment or on extremely large projects and is
                    most likely still FTPing files around. I take
                    version control
                    one step further. Not only do I use the<a href="http://git-scm.com/">Git version control
                    system</a>, I also run my own Git server
                    with<a href="https://github.com/sitaramc/gitolite">Gitolite</a>. Many people who aren't able to
                    run their own server also use
                    <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>
                    which works
                    really well too. If I am stuck dealing with FTP, I'll use something like
                    <a href="https://github.com/scttnlsn/dandelion" target="_blank">Dandelion</a>
                    if
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rsync" target="_blank">Rsync</a>
                    or Git deployment is unavailable.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Pre-compilers</headline>
                <body>
                    Every developer is going to say they know CSS. What this really means, is that they understand
                    how to
                    position and style DOM elements. Once again, I take this further. I use
                    <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">Sass</a>
                    to
                    organize, optimize and generate cross-device/browser code. I also incorporate CSS3 transitions
                    and transforms over JS whenever possible to take advantage of the accelerated performance. What
                    this
                    means for a client, is simply that I create more organized code and faster load times.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>CSS Resetting</headline>
                <body>
                    I use
                    <a href="http://html5boilerplate.com/">HTML5 Boilerplate</a>
                    to ensure that CSS is as consistent as possible when starting a
                    project. Technically, I use a custom repo first started with
                    <a href="http://www.initializr.com/" target="_blank">Initializr</a>
                    which includes HTML5 Boilerplate,
                    <a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/">Twitter's Bootstrap</a>
                    and a few others.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>
                    Browser testing
                </headline>
                <body>
                    I use
                    <a href="http://www.parallels.com/products/desktop/">Parallels Desktop</a>
                    and sometimes
                    <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/" target="_blank">Virtual Box</a>
                    with Windows XP and 7 to test IE6-9. Chrome, Firefox, iOS and Safari are
                    tested
                    on the Mac side. I also use a few Andriod tablets and the iOS simulator.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Mobile styling and functionality</headline>
                <body>
                    What happens when a project is viewed on a mobile device? Suffice it to say it's a major
                    consideration on projects I work on. I'm intimately familiar with Apple's iOS developer
                    guidelines
                    for mobile web development. Many developers don't consider
                    <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2008/01/23/how-web-clips-work/" target="_blank">Webclips</a>
                    or High-PPI screens. I do.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>JavaScript</headline>
                <body>
                    Most developers are going to say they know JavaScript but since JavaScript is a separate art in
                    it's
                    own right, I encourage prospective clients to understand the level that someone really
                    knows
                    JavaScript. I don't simply modify JavaScript or use a framework like JQuery. I write
                    <em>custom</em>
                    JavaScript that follows the MVC design pattern utilizing
                    <a href="http://documentcloud.github.com/backbone/">Backbone.js</a>
                    and<a href="http://jquery.com/">JQuery</a>. If you're
                    interested in developing a polished site or application which includes as much
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajax_(programming)">AJAX</a>
                    functionality as
                    you can muster, you must develop in a way that allows you to organize large quantities of code.
                    Mixing
                    data into the DOM is a great way to have parts of your site fail when it reaches a high
                    complexity level. When I say I know JavaScript, I really know it.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>RequireJS</headline>
                <body>
                    It's important to make sure that all script files are loaded and loaded in a specific order. I
                    use
                    <a href="http://requirejs.org/">require.js</a>
                    for this function. If you're a developer and are using a ton of JavaScript files on
                    your
                    project, I encourage you to start using a module loader like RequireJS as it will help you
                    improve
                    the quality and speed of your code.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>API</headline>
                <body>Many projects require pushing and pulling content from a database. Good developers will write
                    clean
                    code to interface with the database. Great developers will use an
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-relational_mapping">ORM</a>
                    tool so they can simply
                    write
                    less code to interface with the database. Awesome developers will create an
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface">API</a>
                    (with a
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_State_Transfer">REST</a>
                    interface) to utilize an ORM tool so other sites, web services and applications can access data.
                    Truly exceptional developers take it one step even further and use a REST server.
                    Many people will look at this and say the good developer that just writes clean code to
                    interface
                    with the database directly is all their project needs so why spend time (thus money) doing all
                    that? What
                    they
                    wouldn't realize is that it's actually faster to develop with these tools. Using a REST API and
                    ORM
                    tool is faster, cleaner, more maintainable and extensible than interfacing with the database
                    directly so there's really no reason not to go that route except one. Knowledge.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>ORM</headline>
                <body>
                    I'll spare you from the technobabble but basically an ORM tool allows you to write a lot less
                    code
                    to work with a database to accomplish the exact same things. It also helps keep things
                    organized.
                    Personally, I use either
                    <a href="http://redbeanphp.com/">RedbeanPHP</a>
                    or the native
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_record_pattern" target="_blank">active record
                        pattren
                    </a>
                    syntax found in many frameworks like<a href="http://codeigniter.com/" target="_blank">
                    CodeIgniter</a>.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Templating</headline>
                <body>
                    For large-scale deployments, I use both
                    <a href="http://twig.sensiolabs.org/">Twig</a>
                    and on the JavaScript side,<a href="http://api.jquery.com/category/plugins/templates/">JQuery
                    templates</a>. On mid to small
                    projects or projects where other team members may not be familiar with those, I'll usually just
                    use the templating tool that's part of whatever framework is being used.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>REST Server</headline>
                <body>
                    I like CodeIgniter's controllers for creating most APIs as it's one of the fastest in terms of
                    performance
                    but I will also sometimes use a modified
                    <a href="http://jacwright.com/250/simple-rest-server-in-php-supports-json-amf/">rest server</a>
                    originally created by Jacob Wright that uses PHP introspection to
                    map
                    HTTP requests as defined in code comments to specific class methods. The server is also
                    responsible
                    for translating and escaping data to
                    <a href="http://www.json.org/">JSON</a>
                    as well and managing the various HTTP verbs (GET, POST, PUT, DELETE and UPDATE).
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>JQuery</headline>
                <body>
                    If you're reading this, you likely already know what
                    <a href="http://jquery.com/">JQuery</a>
                    is since it's now on more than half of all websites, but if you don't, it's basically a
                    tool (framework) to write less JavaScript and have that JavaScript function consistently across
                    platforms. I use JQuery extensively in most interactive projects but can drop down to Javascript
                    syntax if need be. I also write custom JQuery plugins occasionally should one unlikely not
                    exist.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Debugging Tools</headline>
                <body>
                    I use<a href="http://www.charlesproxy.com/">Charles Proxy</a>,
                    <a href="http://getfirebug.com/">Firebug</a>
                    and
                    <a href="http://www.deltopia.com/compare-merge-sync/macosx/">Deltawalker</a>
                    in addition to the IDE. You can find out what each
                    of
                    these are via the links. When something doesn't work right, you want someone who can find out
                    why
                    and find out quickly.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Documentation</headline>
                <body>
                    Any good developer will comment their code for others. I also use<a
                        href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>,
                    <a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnigraffle/" target="_blank">Omnigraffle</a>, and
                    wikis to help document code should it make sense on a project.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Working Locally</headline>
                <body>
                    I use
                    <a href="http://www.mamp.info/en/mamp-pro/">MAMP Pro</a>
                    to create virtual machines and map development URLs to local vhosts. In a
                    nutshell, I create projects on my computer before I push them up to a staging or live production
                    server. How do I push them up?
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_Transfer_Protocol" target="_blank">FTP</a>
                    is slow and insecure
                    so I use a Git post-hook to keep production, stage and dev locations in sync with remote repos.
                    In layman's terms, that means I can update a
                    site with a single click and that update happens faster and in such a way that's easy to fix
                    should a file get narfed by someone else.
                    If you are a developer and would like to read more specifics, you can
                    <a href="http://wiki.creativeacceleration.com/index.php/Git_as_a_deployment_mechanism"
                       target="_blank">check out
                    </a>
                    how we do it.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>
                    Database Management
                </headline>
                <body>
                    I use
                    <a href="http://www.navicat.com/">Navicat</a>
                    and the CLI to manage my databases. For those wondering, it would replace the need for
                    <a href="http://www.phpmyadmin.net/home_page/index.php">PHPMyAdmin</a>
                    when using a GUI.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Issue Tracking</headline>
                <body>
                    I've used a few tools including
                    <a href="http://www.atlassian.com/software/jira/overview" target="_blank">Jira</a>
                    and
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lighthouse" target="_blank">Lighthouse</a>
                    but perfer<a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/youtrack/" target="_blank">YouTrack</a>.
                    If you'd like to know why, just<a href="mailto:jason@jasonchaney.com">ask</a>.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Video Fallbacks</headline>
                <body>
                    I'm still looking for a preference but I generally use a JavaScript library like the
                    <a href="http://www.kaltura.org/project/HTML5_Video_Media_JavaScript_Library">Kartura Media
                        Library
                    </a>
                    to provide Flash
                    replacement to HTML5 video if the video element is unsupported. This ensures that video and
                    audio content is compatible on all
                    devices
                    and platforms.
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Speed</headline>
                <body>I'd like to end this with one more point. If you hand off a comp (a layered Photoshop file)
                    for a developer to bring to life, will they separate out each multi-layer element
                    as a separate image with 2 or less clicks? Do you want someone knowledgeable about
                    time-savers like<a href="http://www.mightymeta.co.uk/superslicr-ditch-the-slice-tool/"
                                       target="_blank">this</a>? I'm always looking for more efficient ways to do
                    things.

                    If you value that, let's chat.
                </body>
            </point>
        </points>
        <close>
            As you can see, there are many aspects and tools to creating the rich interactive experiences
            that
            people expect. It's important to make sure that you know when and how to use them. Not using
            these
            tools, means development will take longer, cost more, be harder to maintain in the future and is
            generally more prone to fail. As a prospective client, you'll need to decide who you want to hire for
            your
            project.
        </close>
    </process>
    <portfolio>
        <title>My Kung Fu</title>
        <subtitle>These are for you.</subtitle>
        <body>
            Here's some examples of projects I've had the privilege of working on for various clients.
        </body>
        <samples>
            <sample>
                <title>Skype Stay Together</title>
                <client>Uncorked Studios / Microsoft</client>
                <image>img/source_art/skype_stay_together.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/skype_stay_together.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>responsive</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Skype Stay Together</title>
                <client>Uncorked Studios / Microsoft</client>
                <image>img/source_art/skype_stay_together2.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/skype_stay_together2.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>responsive</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Hawaii Here</title>
                <client>Tenfour / Hawaiian Airlines</client>
                <image>img/source_art/hawaii_here.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/hawaii_here.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>mobile</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Hawaii Here</title>
                <client>Tenfour / Hawaiian Airlines</client>
                <image>img/source_art/hawaii_here2.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/hawaii_here2.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>mobile</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Hawaii Here</title>
                <client>Tenfour / Hawaiian Airlines</client>
                <image>img/source_art/hawaii_here2.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/hawaii_here2.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>mobile</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>DIRECTV Goes to School</title>
                <client>DIRECTV</client>
                <image>img/source_art/DIRECTV_Goes_to_School.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/DIRECTV_Goes_to_School.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>DIRECTV Goes to School</title>
                <client>DIRECTV</client>
                <image>img/source_art/DIRECTV_Goes_to_School2.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/DIRECTV_Goes_to_School2.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>IHG</title>
                <client>IHG / XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/source_art/IHG.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/IHG.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Lord of the Rings</title>
                <client>Warner Bros. / The Ant Farm</client>
                <image>img/source_art/Lord_of_the_Rings.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Lord_of_the_Rings.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Shrek</title>
                <client>Warner Bros. / The Ant Farm</client>
                <image>img/source_art/Shrek.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Shrek.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Sodexo</title>
                <client>Sodexo / XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/source_art/Sodexo.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Sodexo.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>T-Mobile</title>
                <client>T-Mobile / XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/source_art/t-mobile.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/t-mobile.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>The OC</title>
                <client>Fox / Creative Asylum</client>
                <image>img/source_art/the_oc.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/the_oc.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Trick r' Treat</title>
                <client>Warner Bros / The Ant Farm</client>
                <image>img/source_art/Trick-r-Treat.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Trick-r-Treat.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Trap.it</title>
                <client>Trap.it / Uncorked Studios</client>
                <image>img/source_art/trapit.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/trapit.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Stratos</title>
                <client>Red Bull / Instrument</client>
                <image>img/source_art/stratos.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/stratos.jpg</thumb>
                <description>FPO Description</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
        </samples>
    </portfolio>
    <experiences>
        <experience>
            <location>
                Uncorked Studios
            </location>
            <position>
                Senior Front-end Developer
            </position>
            <dates>
                2013 to Present
            </dates>
            <functions>
                <function>Develop NodeJS blah blah</function>
            </functions>
        </experience>
    </experiences>
    <skills>
        
    </skills>
    <quotes>
        <quote>
            <body></body>
            <author></author>
            <source></source>
        </quote>
    </quotes>
    <oneoffs>
        <responsive>
            <![CDATA[
            I specialize in mobile web development.  I'm keenly aware of often overlooked details such as IE10's snap mode,
            handling pointer/touch events correctly, GPU accelerated animation, and
            <a href="https://gist.github.com/jchaney01/5777866" target="_blank">mobile-first Sass techniques</a>.
            ]]>
        </responsive>
        <fullstack>
            <![CDATA[
                 I'm a full stack front end developer which means I work the entire development verticle.
                 I use <a href="https://github.com/bower/bower" target="_blank">Bower</a>
                 , <a href="http://getcomposer.org/" target="_blank">Composer</a>
                 , <a href="http://gruntjs.com/" target="_blank">Grunt</a>
                 , <a href="http://us.php.net/" target="_blank" >PHP</a>
                 , <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/" target="_blank">MongoDB</a>
                 , <a href="http://nodejs.org/" target="_blank">NodeJS</a>
                 , <a href="http://backbonejs.org/" target="_blank" >Backbone</a>, <a href="http://requirejs.org/" target="_blank">RequireJS</a>
                 , and web sericve APIs.
            ]]>
        </fullstack>
    </oneoffs>
</root>