<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!--This XML file contains all the copy for the site. Edit as needed.-->
<root>
    <meta>
        <title>Jason Chaney | Mobile Web Application Development</title>
    </meta>
    <intro>I am a seasoned web developer that adheres to the highest level of semantic standards and architectures. I
        have 13 years of cutting-edge experience working for agencies, direct clients, companies and individuals.
        My passion is rooted in finding efficiency in digital communication though visual arts. I have experience
        leading distributed development teams, executing social campaigns, utilizing/building web services, prototyping
        new concepts, developing mobile initiatives and optimizing workflows.
    </intro>
    <about>
        <title>Who is this Guy?</title>
        <subtitle>I'm an autodidactic full-stack mobile front-end developer...with 20 years experience.</subtitle>
        <culture>
            <title>
                My Culture
            </title>
            <body>
                <![CDATA[
                <p>
                The techniques, tools and architecture patterns used to create the modern web literally change
                everyday. As a professional developer, I consider it my responsibility to constantly keep up. I
                listen to podcasts, follow industry leaders and collaborate with other professionals
                daily to ensure I'm using the latest resources available when project crunch time hits.</p>
                ]]>
            </body>
        </culture>
        <body>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>I specialize in building responsive, mobile-first interactive solutions that ooze sweet pixely nectar. I focus on
                usability and architecture while
                ensuring code conforms to the highest level of web and
                <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming">OOP</a>
                semantic standards. I enjoy keeping up with bleeding-edge tools, techniques and new technologies.
                Check out
                <a href="#process">my process</a> to hear how.
            </p>
            ]]>
        </body>
        <freetime>
            <title>
                In My Free Time
            </title>
            <dad>
                <title>Dad</title>
                <image>img/Jason-Chaney.jpg</image>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    I have two beautiful twin
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/20130522-184111.jpg" target="_blank">daughters</a>
                    that keep my wife and me on our toes. We keep a family
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com" target="_blank">blog</a>
                    for
                    friends and family to keep up with the Chaney's
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/archives/1763" target="_blank">antics</a>.
                    ]]>
                </body>
            </dad>
            <technology>
                <title>Technology</title>
                <image>img/segway.jpg</image>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    I enjoy making
                    <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QWfmhuk8cAM" target="_blank">tutorials</a>
                    for other developers, <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/archives/617" target="_blank">hacking</a>
                    a baby swing,
                    <a href="http://meetthechaneys.com/wp/archives/953" target="_blank">pulling my kids</a>

                    behind my
                    Segway
                    or learning new technologies like <a href="http://codeception.com/" target="_blank">Codeception</a>.
                    ]]>
                </body>

            </technology>
            <code>
                <title>Code</title>
                <image>img/jason_workstation.jpg</image>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                        I love all things code.
                            Finding new ways to optimize a method, app, animation or even my monitor setup makes me
                            jump up like <a href="img/boris.jpg" target="_blank">Boris</a>
                         in Goldeneye.  In fact, this entire site is powered by one <a href="/data" target="_blank">data file</a>.
                    ]]>
                </body>
            </code>
        </freetime>
    </about>
    <contact>
        <title>Get in Touch</title>
        <subtitle>If you think I can help out on a project, drop me a line.</subtitle>
        <name>Jason Chaney</name>
        <address>5120 Hill Villa Ave S</address>
        <company>creativeFEW, Inc.</company>
        <city>Salem</city>
        <state>OR</state>
        <zip>97306</zip>
        <country>US</country>
        <phone>310-433-6322</phone>
        <email>
            jchaney@creativefew.com
        </email>
    </contact>
    <process>
        <title>
            My Process
        </title>
        <subtitle>What separates me from other developers?</subtitle>
        <body>
            <![CDATA[
            If you ask a developer what they use to make a website, one might say <a
                href="http://www.adobe.com/products/dreamweaver.html" target="_blank">Dreamweaver</a>,
            another might say
            <a href="http://wordpress.org/" target="_blank">Wordpress</a>
            and another might
            say
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_(text_editor)">Vim</a>
            or <a href="http://nodejs.org/" target="_blank">Node</a>.

            Just this one answer can tell you tons about the nature of those developers. While it doesn't
            necessarily provide a way to know which one might be more skilled at software architecture, it does
            tell
            you which one probably has more knowledge that reaches beyond the average script-kiddies.
              ]]>
        </body>
        <asside>
            I have talked to many developers who say they know JavaScript, when in fact what they really know is
            how
            to modify
            <a href="http://jquery.com/" target="_blank">jQuery</a>
            code. What I do here is outline the general approach and tools I use for interactive project
            construction. This should give you a good idea as to the type of developer I am.
        </asside>
        <points>
            <point>
                <headline>JavaScript</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Most developers are going to say they know JavaScript but since JavaScript is a separate art in
                    it's
                    own right, I encourage prospective clients to really understand the level that someone
                    knows
                    JavaScript. I don't simply modify JavaScript libraries or use a DOM manipulation tool like JQuery. I write
                    <em>custom</em>
                    JavaScript that follows the
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model%E2%80%93view%E2%80%93controller" target="_blank">MVC</a>
                    design pattern utilizing tools like <a target="_blank" href="http://angularjs.org/">Angular</a>
                    ,
                    <a target="_blank" href="http://documentcloud.github.com/backbone/">Backbone</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://requirejs.org/">RequireJS</a>,
                    <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node</a> and <a href="http://jade-lang.com/" target="_blank">Jade</a>. When I say I know JavaScript, I really know it.]]>
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>CSS</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Again, all developers are going to say they know CSS but how many understand why and when to use an <a href="http://css-tricks.com/examples/IconFont/" target="_blank">icon-font</a>, manage high-density displays, integrate
                     view transitions, handle gestures in the presentation layer or manage complex z-index states? I do.
                     ]]>
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Build Process</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Web applications have grown to a complexity level that they now require more robust techniques
                    for deployment, performance optimization and overall organization. The industry-standard tools for doing
                    this is
                    <a href="http://gruntjs.com/" target="_blank">Grunt</a> or <a href="http://gulpjs.com/" target="_blank">Gulp</a>
                    ,
                    and I love to find
                    ever-efficient ways to use it for tasks like image compression, code compilation, linting, minifying and running automated acceptance tests.]]>
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Version Control</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    There are only benefits to using Git so any developer that doesn't, usually hasn't worked in teams.  I understand
                    feature branches, rebases, resolving merge conflicts, hooks, and even <a href="http://git-scm.com/docs/git-reflog" target="_blank">reflog</a>.
                    I love <a href="http://danbarber.me/using-git-for-deployment/" target="_blank">Git deployment</a> but if I am stuck dealing with FTP, I'll use something like
                    <a href="https://github.com/scttnlsn/dandelion" target="_blank">Dandelion</a>. If <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rsync" target="_blank">Rsync</a> is at least an option, I'll use
                    <a href="https://github.com/jedrichards/grunt-rsync" target="_blank">grunt-rsync</a> so I can automate deployment as part of my build process]]>
                    .
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Pre-compilers</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Every developer is going to say they know CSS. What this really means, is that they understand
                    how to
                    position and style DOM elements. I take this further with
                    <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">Sass</a> and the
                    <a href="http://compass-style.org/" target="_blank">Compass</a>
                    framework
                    to
                    organize, optimize and generate cross-device/browser code. I also use <a href="https://gist.github.com/jchaney01/5777866" target="_blank">custom Sass mixins</a>
                     to further organize mobile-first styles.  Many developers don't consider things like
                    <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2008/01/23/how-web-clips-work/" target="_blank">Webclips</a>
                   when coding. I do.  What
                    this
                    means for a client, is simply that I create more organized code with faster load times.]]>
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>REST</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Today's applications don't just consume data from 3rd party sources, but also need to supply data; even if it's to its own user interface.
                    I follow strict <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_State_Transfer">REST</a> principles so when another
                    developer takes over my work, he/she should be able to easily understand how the application works.
                   ]]>
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>Community</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    I love the developer community.  I provide quite a few tutorials for other developers on my YouTube channel with my <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QWfmhuk8cAM" target="_blank">tutorial on Git</a>
                     being especially popular.
                   ]]>
                </body>
            </point>
            <point>
                <headline>
                    Browser testing
                </headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Today's interactive applications must run on many platforms.  The average project I do is tested in over 30 browser versions.
                    I personally own most software platforms and test locally including Microsoft's Surface Pro, Android, iOS, and can emulate all desktop browsers.]]>
                </body>
            </point>

            <point>
                <headline>Testing</headline>
                <body>
                    <![CDATA[
                    Unit, functional and acceptance testing is the practice of writing code that checks parts of the application for errors.
                    This practice usually results in more stable code with less bugs.  When I write tests, I usually use <a href="http://codeception.com/" target="_blank">Codeception</a>
                     or <a href="https://github.com/pivotal/jasmine" target="_blank">Jasmine</a>.
                   ]]>
                </body>
            </point>
        </points>
        <close>
            <![CDATA[
            As you can see, there are many aspects to creating the rich interactive experiences
            that
            people expect. Using the right tools and techniques means development will cost less, the app will be easier to maintain and is
            generally less prone to fail. As a prospective client, you'll need to decide if these things are valuable to your next project.
            ]]>
        </close>
    </process>
    <portfolio>
        <title>My Kung Fu</title>
        <subtitle>These are for you.</subtitle>
        <body>
            <![CDATA[
            Here's some examples of projects I've had the privilege of working on for various clients.  My
            <a href="/resume">r&eacute;sum&eacute;</a>
            contains live URLs.
            ]]>
        </body>
        <samples>
            <sample>
                <title>Benchmade Customizer</title>
                <client>Pollinate / Benchmade</client>
                <image>img/work/full/benchmade1.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/benchmade.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I was the primary developer on this responsive AngularJS/HTML5 Canvas and Node application.  Users can customize all aspects of a knife including uploading their own art, custom text and blade shapes.  Customizations animate on screen using HTML5 Canvas, handles are programmatically colorized and final renders are generated with Node and sent to the engraver machines.</description>
                <category>Application</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Skype Stay Together</title>
                <client>Uncorked Studios / Microsoft</client>
                <image>img/work/full/skype_stay_together.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/skype_stay_together.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I was one of two Front-end developers for this Wordpress
                    responsive site which allowed users to read submitted stories as well as view those stories
                    geographically.
                    This image shows the primary responsive touch desktop slider for all media on the story pages.
                </description>
                <category>responsive</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Hawaii Here</title>
                <client>Tenfour / Hawaiian Airlines</client>
                <image>img/work/full/hawaii_here.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/hhMark.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I was the Front-end developer for this jQuery Mobile Ruby on Rails project. The mobile web
                    app allows users to view places of interest based on their location as well as view their Hawaiian
                    Airlines account.
                </description>
                <category>mobile</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Yopine</title>
                <client>Uncorked Studios</client>
                <image>img/work/full/yopine.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/yopine.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I was one of several developers that helped launch Yopine. A native iOS app with Node/Socket.io web counterpart that allows users to create and send polls to their friends where each person can vote and see results in realtime.
                </description>
                <category>mobile</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Biz Dev Showcase</title>
                <client>XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/work/full/biz_dev_showcase.png</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/biz_dev_showcase.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I created this application to allow business development managers to create microsites that show off collections of case studies and work samples.
                </description>
                <category>Application</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>DIRECTV Goes to School</title>
                <client>DIRECTV</client>
                <image>img/work/full/gts.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/gts.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I did both the backend and frontend for this CMS-powered Laravel/Angular site which also collects
                    customer information.
                </description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>IHG</title>
                <client>IHG / XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/work/full/IHG.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/IHG.jpg</thumb>
                <description>International Hotels Group was using an elaborate Excel file to calculate their OTA
                    dependencies. I converted the calculation tool to a web application complete with animated visuals
                    of the calculation result.
                </description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Lord of the Rings</title>
                <client>Warner Bros. / The Ant Farm</client>
                <image>img/work/full/Lord_of_the_Rings.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Lord_of_the_Rings.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This Flash site for the Home Entertainment release of the film uses 3D rendered videos to
                    play various trailers.
                </description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Shrek</title>
                <client>Warner Bros. / The Ant Farm</client>
                <image>img/work/full/Shrek.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Shrek.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This Flash puzzle app was used to promote the upcoming release of the film.</description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Sodexo</title>
                <client>Sodexo / XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/work/full/Sodexo.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Sodexo.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This Flash exploratory app walks the user though the Sodexo service offerings.
                </description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Rocky Peak Essentials</title>
                <client>The Church at Rocky Peak</client>
                <image>img/work/full/essentials.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/essentials.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This site was created to allow members to view and download video and audio courses. The
                    site is powered by Amazon's S3.
                </description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>T-Mobile</title>
                <client>T-Mobile / XPLANE</client>
                <image>img/work/full/t-mobile.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/t-mobile.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This app for T-Mobile was used by in-store employees to showcase how T-Mobile and the
                    Galaxy Tab can enhance user's lives by showcasing real world uses.
                </description>
                <category>app</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>The OC</title>
                <client>Fox / Creative Asylum</client>
                <image>img/work/full/the_oc.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/the_oc.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This Flash site was created for the Home Entertainment release of the series on DVD.
                </description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Trick r' Treat</title>
                <client>Warner Bros / The Ant Farm</client>
                <image>img/work/full/Trick-r-Treat.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/Trick-r-Treat.jpg</thumb>
                <description>This Flash site was created for the Home Entertainment release of the film.</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Trap.it</title>
                <client>Trap.it / Uncorked Studios</client>
                <image>img/work/full/trapit.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/trapit.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I was one of two NodeJS developers for the Trap.it website.</description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
            <sample>
                <title>Stratos</title>
                <client>Red Bull / Instrument</client>
                <image>img/work/full/stratos.jpg</image>
                <thumb>img/work/thumbs/stratos.jpg</thumb>
                <description>I created this responsive SPA which details the story of Red Bull's Stratos - The highest
                    jump on record.
                </description>
                <category>website</category>
            </sample>
        </samples>
    </portfolio>
    <experiences>
        <experience>
            <location>
                Uncorked Studios
            </location>
            <position>
                Contract Front-end Developer
            </position>
            <dates>
                3/2013 to 7/2013
            </dates>
            <functions>
                <function>Developed Node.js/MongoDB, PHP and Wordpress mobile-web applications.</function>
                <function>Automate deployment workflows</function>
                <function>Develop complex responsive sites for global brands</function>
                <function>Interface with native iOS developers to ensure application consistency and performance
                </function>
                <function>Cross-device/browser debugging</function>
            </functions>
        </experience>
        <experience>
            <location>Tenfour Agency</location>
            <position>Senior Frontend Developer</position>
            <dates>2012 to 2013</dates>
            <functions>
                <function>
                    Worked with other developers to create mobile web applications that integrate with a variety of
                    social and 3rd-party APIs.
                </function>
                <function>Develop modern cross-browser responsive layouts with an emphasis on mobile UX</function>
                <function>Interfaced with UX and design leads to implement technical optimizations</function>
                <function>Create custom CMS tools for data population and consumption</function>
            </functions>
        </experience>
        <experience>
            <location><![CDATA[Dachis Group &mdash; acquired XPLANE]]></location>
            <position>Technologist</position>
            <dates>2011 t0 2012</dates>
            <functions>
                <function>Developed social and web apps for global brands mainly in LAMP and Ruby environments
                </function>
                <function>Optimized development process by automating project life-cycle workflow tools</function>
                <function>Converted Flash applications to HTML5/CSS/JS equivalents</function>
                <function>Led development teams on larger engagements ensuring progress and quality milestones were
                    met
                </function>
                <function>Scoped interactive projects for quick-turn RFP responses</function>
                <function>Technical liaison between Project Managers and Account Managers</function>
            </functions>
        </experience>
        <experience>
            <location>XPLANE</location>
            <position>Technologist</position>
            <dates>2009 to 2011</dates>
            <functions>
                <function>Developed desktop web and tablet web apps for international clients mainly in a LAMP
                    environment
                </function>
                <function>Architect for new client delivery platform with web services integration</function>
                <function>Developed custom CMS as well as Wordpress interactive projects</function>
                <function>Interfaced with native mobile developers and designers to ensure technical and nontechnical QA
                    requirements were being met
                </function>
                <function>Established an in-house development team</function>
                <function>Technology lead on all interactive projects</function>
                <function>Performed all Linux, font and Git server administration</function>
                <function>Wrote technical documentation for clients and staff</function>
            </functions>
        </experience>
        <experience>
            <location>Creative Acceleration, Inc.</location>
            <position>Freelance Front-End
                Developer
            </position>
            <dates>2004 to present</dates>
            <functions>
                <function>Work directly with entertainment clients to establish scope and technical requirements
                </function>
                <function>Create functional sites from PSD comps</function>
                <function>Establish Git and Issue tracking workflows</function>
                <function>Interface with designers to ensure technical feasibility</function>
                <function>Debug Javascript, PHP and CSS issues</function>
                <function>Linux server administration for client servers</function>
                <function>Develop web apps for national brands using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and PHP/MySQL</function>
            </functions>
        </experience>
    </experiences>
    <skills>
        <![CDATA[
        Expert proficiency with Angular and the LAMP stack, Grunt/Gulp and CSS. I'm
        fluent with Git (including hooks), CSS3 (including Sass and responsive layouts with
        animation), native HTML5 JS APIs, Markdown, cross-browser IE nonsense, Apache/Nginx configuration,
        agile workflows, reflow optimizations and social APIs. Some familiarity with Objective-C (iOS SDK 5-6),
        Appcelerator (similar to PhoneGap), Wordpress, Ruby/Rails, Sinatra and Heroku.
        ]]>
    </skills>
    <quotes>
        <quote>
            <body>@jchaney01 Thanks for the GREAT git/tower tutorial on YouTube! Many 'light bulb' moments for me.
            </body>
            <author>Edward Alton via Twitter</author>
            <source></source>
        </quote>
    </quotes>
    <oneoffs>
        <responsive>
            <![CDATA[
            I specialize in mobile web development.  I'm keenly aware of often overlooked details such as IE's snap mode,
            handling pointer/touch events correctly, GPU accelerated animation, and
            <a href="https://gist.github.com/jchaney01/5777866" target="_blank">mobile-first Sass techniques</a>.
            ]]>
        </responsive>
        <fullstack>
            <![CDATA[
                 I'm a full stack front-end developer which means I work the entire development verticle.
                 I use <a href="https://github.com/bower/bower" target="_blank">Bower</a>
                 , <a href="http://getcomposer.org/" target="_blank">Composer</a>
                 , <a href="http://gruntjs.com/" target="_blank">Grunt</a>
                 , <a href="http://us.php.net/" target="_blank" >PHP</a>
                 , <a href="http://angularjs.org/" target="_blank" >Angular</a>
                 , <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/" target="_blank">MongoDB</a>
                 , <a href="http://nodejs.org/" target="_blank">NodeJS</a>
                 , <a href="http://backbonejs.org/" target="_blank" >Backbone</a>, <a href="http://requirejs.org/" target="_blank">RequireJS</a>
                 , and web sericve APIs.
            ]]>
        </fullstack>
    </oneoffs>
</root>